Some passions can never be tamed.
All the Pretty Horses is a drama, romance, western
film directed by Billy Bob Thornton.
The year is 1949.
A young Texan named John Grady finds himself without a home after his
mother sells the ranch where he has spent his entire life.
Lured south of the border by the romance of cowboy life and the promise of a fresh start, Cole and his pal embark on
an adventure that will test their resilience, define their maturity, and change their lives forever.
John Grady, played by Matt Damon.
Rawlins, played by Henry Thomas.
Blevins, played by Lucas Black.
Alejandra, played by Penélope Cruz.
Rocha, played by Rubén Blades.
Cole, played by Robert Patrick.
All the Pretty Horses is a 2000 American Western film produced and directed by Billy Bob Thornton, based
on Cormac McCarthy's novel of the same name, and starring Matt Damon and Penélope Cruz.
It was released on December 25, 2000, by Miramax Films in the United States and by Columbia Pictures (through
Columbia TriStar Film Distributors International) in other territories to mostly negative reviews.
It grossed $18.1 million worldwide on a $57 million
budget, making it a box office bomb.
All the Pretty Horses was the first film
adaptation from a Cormac McCarthy novel.
The film explores themes of prisoner, falsely accused, beating, corpse, cautery.
The tone is emotional.